

MANUEL CEPPI

Software Developer

+39 3474908550 • manuel.ceppi@outlook.it • https://www.linkedin.com/in/manuel-ceppi/ • https://manuelceppi.dev/ • Italy

https://github.com/ManuelCeppi

Summary

With 6 years of professional experience, I've had the opportunity to work on diverse projects and technologies, collaborating with various IT businesses and software development teams. This exposure has honed my ability to work with others right from the start of my career. Beyond technical skills, I bring a strong emphasis on building positive team relationships and fostering an environment of empathy, understanding, and respect. I strive to understand the unique perspectives of my colleagues, seeing it as essential to developing effective and resilient teams. I'm committed to continuous improvement in both my professional and personal development, dedicating myself fully to achieve the goals and objectives set by the company I join.

Experience

@Side Projects / Certifications / Personal Growth

Remote, Italy

Senior Software Developer

09/2024 - Present

Stack - Supabase / Vue.js / Vercel / GitHub Actions / Python / AWS Lambda / PostgreSQL

MVP Development / Side projects and certifications

- Successfully developed an MVP (Backend) for a startup idea in GenAI with only the prompting costs, from the technical aspects to building and thinking about a sustainable business model; Built a business plan to present to potential investors, with the partnership of an Italian Business angel;
- Currently building a finance investment ranker dashboard that will manage and rank stocks through different metrics by analyzing 4mln+ worth of stocks data;
- Currently pursuing the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner certification issued by Amazon Web Services;
- Improving my knowledge on DSA / Cloud / Design patterns;

@Spiagge.it Remote, Italy

Senior Software Developer

08/2022 - 08/2024

SaaS - Startup software house

Stack - PHP (Laravel) / Vue.js / Docker / AWS / MySQL / Stripe

- Led the end-to-end integration of TeamSystem ERP to manage accounts payable/receivable, automating invoice creation and streamlining administrative workflows.
- Developed a system using Stripe webhooks to automate tracking and invoicing for connected account payouts, generating up to 1,000 invoices
 weekly during peak seasons.
- Designed a refund management system with a back-office interface, integrated with Stripe's refund APIs, enhancing processing speed by 50% (no more double checks on Stripe Dashboard).
- Integrated Brizy, a white-label website builder, enabling customers to create websites, generating a new revenue stream that exceeded sales projections by 1,000%.
- Built a compliant third-party invoicing system, saving ~500k€ in anticipated VAT taxes.
- Contributed to the migration to serverless and microservices architecture, reducing errors by 10-15% in payments, invoices, and refunds.
- Created AWS dashboards and alarms to enhance error detection and exception handling.

@Fortech S.r.l. Rimini, Italy

Software Developer 12/2021 - 08/2022

Software House

Stack -. Net Core / Angular / MSSQL.

- Improved warehouse management by reducing errors by 15% through architectural and graphic refactoring for EniCafés;
- Enhanced performance by 30% implementing a master/slave service architecture and backend caching patterns to reduce database queries;

Experience

@Horsa DevLab (previously Wedo S.R.L)

Junior Software Developer

Cesena, Italy 01/2018 - 12/2021

Software House

Stack -. Net Core / Angular / Vue.js / MSSQL / Kotlin

- Developed multiple add-ons for SAP Business One using C# and MSSQL, enhancing performance and tailoring the ERP to meet specific business
- · Contributed as a full-stack developer to the refactoring and commercial deployment preparation of a business travel web application, built with Angular (2) and .NET Core;

Skills

 $PHP \cdot C\# \cdot Typescript \cdot Python \cdot SQL \cdot NoSQL \cdot MongoDB \cdot MySql \cdot PostgreSQL \cdot MSSQL \cdot Laravel \cdot .NET \ Core \cdot Angular \cdot Vue. \\ js \cdot Docker \cdot AWS \cdot MSSQL \cdot Laravel \cdot .NET \ Core \cdot Angular \cdot Vue. \\ js \cdot Docker \cdot AWS \cdot MSSQL \cdot MSSQ$ AWS Lambda · CI/CD · GitHub · GitHub Actions · Bitbucket · Bitbucket pipelines · Unit Testing · Integration Testing · E2E Testing · DDD · SOLID Principles · GoF Design Patterns · Key-value Storage · Redis

Languages

English Advanced

Italian Native

Strengths



Team collaboration skills

Efficiently collaborates and builds strong team relationships with empathy and respect.



Financial systems integration

Proficient in designing solutions for financial systems and ERP integrations.

Commitment to self-improvement

Constantly seeks out new learning opportunities for both professional and personal growth.



Project development expertise

Ability to develop projects from technical aspects to sustainable business planning.

PERSONAL PROJECTS



manuelceppi.dev

Personal Website, designed by me. AstroJS + TailwindCSS + Vercel. Website Link GitHub Link



AlgoTradingBot

An AWS Lambda that performs algorithmic trading, deployed with GitHub Actions + Serverless Framework, built with python. GitHub Link

Education

Alma Mater Studiorum - University Of Bologna, Italy

B.Sc., Computer Science | Interrupted

Blaise Pascal Technical Institute, Italy

Computer Science Diploma | Grade: **86** / 100